# Nicolas **Rojas**

Applied mathematician | Computer scientist



# **About me**

I am a professional in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, with a focus on artificial intelligence and data science, and currently completing my master's degree in Artificial Intelligence. I have worked developing deep learning models for industrial usage, which includes gathering the necessary data, researching the optimal machine learning model for the given problem, and writing the necessary code to train and deploy the final product

### Personal

Full name: Nicolas Rojas Gutierrez Born: Bogota, Colombia, 2000

# Areas of specialization

Artificial Intelligence · Data Science · Machine Learning Signal Processing

# Interests

My main interest is applying artificial intelligence concepts and algorithms into different researching areas, like computer vision, natural language processing, cybersecurity or quantum computation. Implementing efficient computational solutions to real industry problems and challenges is my current professional objective.

Python · Numpy/Scipy  ${\tt Scikit-Learn} \, \cdot \, {\tt PyTorch}$ TensorFlow · Scikit-Image Spacy · Linux · LATEX · Git





# EXPERIENCE

### 2022-Now Machine learning engineer

Ressolve · Remote ♀

Developer and main maintainer of several natural language processing (NLP) models, to solve text classification, information extraction, information obfuscation, named entity recognition and automatic speech recognition problems. Cloud technologies are used to train and deploy the models

## 2021-2022

# Machine learning intern

Ressolve · Remote ♀

Maintained previously existing company software. This included searching and finding bugs, helping in the development of new machine learning products to comply with the client's requirements, and analyze data from the deployed models to propose new solutions and tools

# 2021-2022

# Freelancer developer

INDEPENDENT · Remote 9

Developed software solutions for several machine learning companies or related projects. These computational solutions included unsupervised learning, semisupervised learning, data analysis, application deployment and data scrapping, depending on the requirements of the contractor



## **Teaching assistant**

Universidad del Rosario · Bogota, COL 9

Assisted several courses, such as Algorithms and Data Structures, Graph theory, Probability and Statistics. Responsibilities included in-class help for the professors, and additional classes for the students that required them



## Research assistant

Universidad del Rosario Bogota, COL 9

Provided technical assistance to researchers in the Engineering school. This included implementing required software, mainly in python, and redacting experimentation results using LATEX



# DEGREES

In progress Master's degree in Artificial

Intelligence

M.Sc. · Universidad Javeriana

2022 Applied mathematician and computer scientist

B.Sc. · Universidad del Rosario

# Numpy, Scipy

**PyTorch** TensorFlow

Programming

**Python** 



# **CERTIFICATES & ACHIEVEMENTS**

### 2023 Academic merit award

HIGH GRADUATE AVERAGE · Universidad Javeriana 🏛



# 2018 Academic merit scholarship HIGH UNDERGRADUATE AVER-

AGE · Universidad del Rosario



# LANGUAGES

Spanish | C2 English

Native speaker C1 TOEFL iBT certificated

